My entire life I lived The Art of the
Deal.
It has been a kind of guiding principle
in so many ways for my entire life. And
I run a top organization every day
that's, you know, I would work with my
father every every second of every day
really until he went to politics. And
you know, I'm his best friend in the
world.
My father wants America to win in
everything we do. My father believes in
winning at energy. He wants to win at
AI. He wants to win at cryptocurrency.
My father ran under the notion of being
the crypto president. He believes in
cryptocurrency. He believes in this
industry. He believes in Bitcoin. He
believes in digital assets. And so, it
makes a lot of sense that everybody in
his, you know, inner circle follows that
same premise. He wouldn't bring somebody
into his inner circle if they didn't
follow that premise. If Europe ever
wants to try and take on cryptocurrency,
they can't do it.
Wait, who didn't do it? Asia would do
it. If we didn't do it, the Middle East
would do it.
>> Is there a possibility where everybody
wins together?
>> Everybody wants the US dollar. You know
what no one wants? They don't want the
euro. They don't want any other
currency. They want the US dollar. We
have the best energy by far in the
world. Go try and do this in in in the
UK. You know, zero chance, right? You
have a you have an economy that, you
know, actually produces 1/6 the amount
of energy that they actually consume.
They don't stand a chance at the AI
race. They don't stand a chance at at at
a crypto race. They don't stand a chance
at mining Bitcoin.
>> What is your favorite childhood memory
with your dad?
>> Building some of Lego skyscrapers on the
office of his the floor of his office
while he's in incredible meetings, being
the fly on on that wall was was amazing.
>> Do you guys tell each other you love
each other?
>> Oh, yeah, all the time. He still calls
me honey.
>> Eric, my name is David Lin.
Uh you guys are out of uh
>> I come out of camera, man.
>> Thank you.
I'm here with Eric Trump, co-founder of
American Bitcoin, and we're going to
talk about the future of of Bitcoin and
company highlights. I'm David Lin. This
is
>> Bonnie Cheung.
>> Eric, welcome to the show. I'm a host to
you. So, Kevin Warsh, the incoming Fed
chair, is known to be a tech-savvy guy.
He's well connected within Silicon
Valley, probably the most tech-savvy Fed
chair in history once he enters office.
Should he assume the role of Fed chair,
which we expect that he will,
what does that mean for the future of
Bitcoin and AI, especially coming from
the comments that he's made? He said
that Bitcoin and AI will be the dominant
drivers of the American economy.
>> Yeah.
Let me break this down. I'm going to
make it very simple. My father wants
America to win at everything we do. My
father believes in winning at energy. He
wants to win at AI. He wants to win at
cryptocurrency. That's his entire
platform. That's his entire mandate. My
father ran under the notion of being the
crypto president. He believes in
cryptocurrency. He believes that, you
know, money can transact in a much more
efficient and a a much
safer and a much more transparent manner
than than ever before. He believes in
this industry. He believes in Bitcoin.
He believes in digital assets. And so,
it makes a lot of sense that everybody
in his, you know, inner circle you know,
follows that same premise. He wouldn't
bring somebody into his inner circle if
they didn't follow that premise. And
it's pretty obvious if you look around
the world. Look at the transformation of
digital assets right now. I mean, look
at the tokenization. Look at what
Bitcoin's done. Look at digital asset
and their growth over the last decade.
It's been absolutely explosive. Then you
combine that with the fact that
obviously we have a pro-crypto
administration, but you we also have
probably the best energy profile of any
country in the world. Not only are we
energy independent in America, we're
actually exporting energy. Good luck if
if Europe ever wants to try and take on
AI. Good luck if Europe ever wants to
try and take on cryptocurrency. They
can't do it because they don't have the
energy profile to do it. And so,
we're going to win this because we're
first. We're also the biggest economy in
the world by far.
You have an administration that's
pushing it. We have the energy resources
to do it.
And so, you have had a 180 in terms of
the directional thinking on
cryptocurrency, you know, since my
father entered office.
You know, Biden was literally throwing
everybody in jail who who dreamed about
possibly being able to conduct finance
better more efficiently a a modern
fashion.
Now all of a sudden you've got a fair
pay chairman who's going to come in and
be fantastic for the industry and also
not only be fantastic for the industry,
actually understand the industry. You
had Biden, you had Kamala Harris who
couldn't spell AI.
You know,
literally they didn't know what they
were talking they didn't they didn't
care to understand it. You have my
father who wants to win this race
and be the best at it in the world. And
by the way, if we didn't do it, Asia
would do it. If we didn't do it, the
Middle East would do it.
And so we're leading the way and that's
what America has to do.
>> Is there a possibility where everybody
wins together?
>> Well, I think so. I mean obviously, you
know,
cryptocurrency is is is digital finance
around the world. I mean, I'm head of,
you know, American Bitcoin. I founded
that company. It's I believe in digital
assets and I could argue that Bitcoin
has as much of a place, maybe even a
greater place in so many markets
internationally than it does even in the
United States as the number one economy
in the world. You look at so many places
that have hyperinflation, that have bad
banks, that have bad governments, that
have instability in the markets, that
have total corruption. You know, what
better place to own Bitcoin than those
places where somebody can't seize your
money in the middle of the night. You
know, an institution can't lose your
money. A capital market can't collapse
and destroy your
your your resources. All of a sudden you
have global liquidity 24 hours a day, 7
days a week. And you know how you do
that? You know, effectively through your
your iPad or your smartphone. I can make
an argument that the global community is
actually the greatest benefactor of this
and actually creates financial
independence and financial freedom
all around the world. It also ties
global finance together in ways that
we've never seen before. I mean,
you know, if I need to send money right
now to to you name it, Morocco. How do I
do it? How do I do it? Meaning if I had
to use a swift wire transfer system, I
find a bank in Morocco. Who do Who am I
talking to? Do I speak the same
language? You know, what what what's the
currency conversion rate? Guess what?
You know what crypto does? It eliminates
all of that. It allows instantaneous
transfer of money all over the world.
So, when you ask if is it going to be
global?
It's 100% global. The whole concept of
cryptocurrency, digital assets is to
make them global. The largest benefactor
of all of that, the United States
because everybody wants the US dollar.
You know what no one wants? They don't
want the euro. They don't want any other
currency. They want the US dollar. And I
so I actually think
>> Yeah.
>> it's a very global initiative, but I
think America's going to be the biggest
benefactor.
>> Talk about American Bitcoin, but what
brings Bitcoin miners to America? So,
Bitcoin miners want a low-cost
jurisdiction when it comes to energy
costs as well as possibly low cost for
capital gains taxes. So, how do we make
mining America beneficial for the miners
themselves?
>> Yeah, well, I think it First of all, you
have a lot of tax policy that does that
in America. You have bonus depreciation
where, you know, you're you're able to
kind of deduct capital. And obviously,
you know, these machines are capital
intensive and these facilities are
capital intensive and the energy
infrastructure is capital intensive,
right? And so, you know, you certainly
do have perks um along with every other
industry in the US. If if you want to
actually invest capital in something,
you know, you have a lot of kind of tax
savings associated with investment in
infrastructure in in this country. Um
second of all, we have the best energy
by far in in the world. Go try and do
this in in in the UK. You know, zero
chance, right? You have a You have an
economy that, you know, you know,
actually produces 1/6 the amount of
energy that they actually consume. They
don't stand a chance at the AI race.
They don't stand a chance at at at the
crypto race. They don't stand a chance
at mining Bitcoin. We have some of the
lowest energy profiles anywhere in the
country. You Then you look at Texas
where America you know, Bitcoin does the
vast majority of its mining. You know,
some of the best energy rates anywhere
on on Earth. And so, we can be
incredibly competitive and you know, we
went public, American Bitcoin, 8 months
and 3 days ago. I know this because we
have our earnings report in about 5
minutes and we're doing great. I mean,
we have well over 7,000 Bitcoin. Well
over. We're going to announce the exact
number in, you know, in in just a little
while. And we built a company from
scratch. We have over 90,000 mining
machines. We have 28 um exahash, over 28
exahash of compute power. We're about,
you know, 2 and 1/2 to 3% of the total
mining worldwide in a company that's
um literally 8 months and 3 days old.
It's It's It's an amazing story and
we're able to do it right here in
America on American soil using American
energy.
America has to be the dominant country
in the world in terms of everything
crypto related in terms of everything
surrounding kind of the digital markets
and digital finance and you know, it's
It's a big goal of mine and it's
something that I'm sprinting at very
very quickly.
>> My question for you is I'm a big fan of
the art of the deal and I actually made
a video on this topic. How does that
influence your view on making deals and
businesses?
>> Yeah.
I think my entire life I lived the art
of the deal.
I was I was born under the art of the
deal. That book came out when I was very
very young and I think it's been kind of
a guiding principle in so many ways for
my entire life. I mean, I run the Trump
Organization every day. That's you know,
I worked with my father every every
second of every day really until he went
to politics and you know, his best
friend in the world and believe me those
lessons were all beaten to us and and
you know, so many of them negotiate
everything and
run very very lean. You we do that all
when it comes to American Bitcoin,
right? I mean, we negotiate everything.
We run extremely extremely lean. We
probably have the lowest SG&A of any
company in the industry. It's not even
close. It's not even close compared to
some of our competitors. We can't even
find competitors that are even in the
same spectrum
of kind of cost structure and and
efficiency that that we run at.
Well, we do that by by by not paying
exorbitant salaries to to CEOs who are
compensated you know, in cash. At the
end of the day, what are we trying to
build? We're trying to build our Bitcoin
holdings, right? So, you know, when when
you're paying you know, executives
hundreds of millions of dollars to run a
a company where that money could have
otherwise been you know, invested in the
asset that's been growing at roughly 70%
a year year-over-year for the last
decade, which do you think is more
creative to shareholder value? You know,
you know, shareholder you know,
executive compensation or or do you
think it's
you know, actually collecting Bitcoin
and holding it
and letting it continue to grow and
appreciate a year after year?
>> how much Bitcoin to hold rather than
sell to the market after you've mined
it.
>> Well, we try and hold every single coin.
Our only premise of our entire company
is to to grow our Bitcoin stack and our
North Star is growing Satoshis per
share.
>> Michael Saylor just said that he may
sell some Bitcoin to finance dividends.
What would make you pivot and decide to
sell some Bitcoin? If somebody were to
ask you, "Hey, could you sell some
Bitcoin?" What would that reason be?
>> It would have to be beyond catastrophic.
>> Okay.
>> Listen, we are we are American
Bitcoin.
>> Mhm.
>> We believe in Bitcoin. You know, come
hell or high water, it would take us a
lot a lot to have to sell our treasury.
The only goal of our entire company is
to grow that treasury.
While you see this entire ecosystem
around the world, I mean, you see what
retail investors are doing. You see what
institutional investors are doing. You
see the largest banks in the country
that are hoarding Bitcoin. You see
Fortune 500 companies that are putting
it on its on its treasuries like never
before. You see, you know, market
structure legislation. You see every
country in the world that's starting to
follow the United States and and and
embrace cryptocurrencies in ways that
the mass adoption of of cryptocurrency
and and Bitcoin specifically, because
Bitcoin is clearly winning that race, is
unlike anything that we've seen before.
And so,
why would you want to get rid of
of of of the asset that we believe to be
the perfect financial instrument? And
so,
our entire premise is to to to hoard as
much. And and we believe there's two
races. We believe there's And Michael's
a dear friend and I know you interviewed
him earlier. I've known Michael for 25
years, long before he was in in
MicroStrategy. But there's two races.
There's the race of who can accumulate
the most.
And and and Michael's done an
unbelievably What what what a visionary
he's been. And then there's the race of
who can do, you know, who can acquire
the most cheapest.
And I can tell you at American Bitcoin,
that's the race we want to win. We want
to be the ones that acquire the most the
cheapest. And when you can mine
something for 50 cents on the dollar,
can you mine Can you Can you farm wheat
for 50 cents on on dollar? Can you farm
corn for 50 cents on the dollar? I mean,
these are facetious and and and and
obviously you can't, it's not even
close. Can you mine gold for 50% on the
dollar? What other kind of commodity,
what other product can you mine at
literally, you know, roughly 50% on the
dollar? And that's what we do at
American Bitcoin every day because of
our infrastructure, because of our
low-cost structure, because of our
energy profile.
Um it's a remarkable business model and
and we're incredibly proud of where
we've come in literally 8 months.
>> Why is Bitcoin important to you
personally?
>> Yeah.
Digital assets are important to me
because we were debanked uh in in in in
in in in in in in the realm of of
American politics, which are brutal. As
they are in every country, yours
included, and certainly in in Canada and
everywhere else, politics are brutal,
but we were debanked by the biggest
banks in the country for doing nothing
wrong. I mean, we we own the best
hotels, best residential buildings, best
commercial buildings,
um the best real estate anywhere on
Earth.
Uh and we were thrown out of so many of
the biggest banks, the JP Morgans, the
Capital Ones, like dogs. 300 accounts
shut down overnight for doing nothing
wrong, all because of politics. And it
drove us into digital assets, it drove
us into the DeFi world, and it drove us
to meet people who were also being
debanked by the very same people who
were debanking us. So, you know, that
old analogy, kind of the,
you know, the enemy of the your enemy is
is your friend, that's exactly what
happened between us and kind of the
crypto industry. And then we met some of
the smartest people that we've ever
seen, um and we started embracing the
industry, we started understanding the
industry,
and then it clicked. And it clicked for
all of us. It clicked for you, it
clicked for you, it it clicked for all
of us. Uh and I've probably become one
of the the greatest proponents worldwide
um of cryptocurrency. And this is coming
from a guy who who spent his entire life
building places
like this, like the ones we're in, hard
assets.
If you would have told me 5, 6, 7 years
ago
that I'd be this passionate about
digital assets, I would have laughed. I
I literally would have laughed at you.
And uh and and there's nothing I'm more
passionate about. Um I love what I'm
doing at American Bitcoin. I love what
we're doing at World Liberty Financial.
I love what we're doing with
stablecoins. I love what we're doing in
the entire ecosystem. And I could not be
more proud of all of it.
>> What was your favorite childhood memory
with your dad?
>> Oh god. I loved running the construction
sites with him. I I loved walking the
construction sites with him. Yeah, it
was you know, walking some of the most
impressive buildings in New York as they
were going up, the steel and concrete,
the superstructures.
Um as a young kid, you know, the the the
tough New York union contractors, but
but some of the best builders anywhere
in the world. Um those memories were
amazing, you know, building kind of LEGO
skyscrapers on the office of his on the
floor of his office while he was in
incredible meetings. Uh being the fly on
on that wall was was amazing, and
he's a remarkable guy. He's doing a hell
of a job for this country. He's my best
friend in the world, and
incredibly proud of him. Incredibly
proud.
>> tell each other you love each other?
>> Oh yeah, all the time. He still calls me
honey, which I I is very funny.
>> love that.
>> "Honey, honey." You know, now I'm I'm a
42-year-old man with with gray in his
beard, and he still calls me honey. And
he actually jokes about it. He goes,
"You know, my kids, I don't care how old
they are. I don't care if you know, they
have kids of their own, and they're
married, you know, they'll always be
they'll always be honey to me." He's a
He's a fantastic guy, and I'm proud of
everything that he's he's achieved, and
I'm proud to run our company, and I'm
I'm certainly proud to be
be be one of the leaders I think in in
the digital asset race, and hopefully
we'll be remembered for for putting a
lot of juice uh on this asset.
>> Well, thank you, Eric. Congratulations
on everything you've done with American
Bitcoin. Look forward to future success.
>> I love this conversation. Thank you.